bookdepository.co.uk 2015-06-26

# Help at Book Depository

### Our privacy policy

 **Summary for people who are not lawyers:**

  * We fully abide by the Data Protection Act.
  * We'll never share, sell or otherwise leverage your data unless you agree to it
  * The information we collect is necessary for the smooth running of an e-commerce website - don't worry, we'll only ask for data that we need.
  * If you have any questions, requests etc just drop us a line and we'll do our best to help

**The full text for people who enjoy reading this sort of thing:**   
This privacy policy sets out how The Book Depository uses and protects any information that you give The Book Depository when you use this website.

The Book Depository is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

This Privacy Policy explains our data processing practices and your options regarding the ways in which your personal data is used. If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any queries with regard to our processing please contact us via the Contact us page.

The Book Depository may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. 

**What we collect**  
We may collect the following information:

  * name and contact information including email address
  * demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
  * information about your purchases
  * other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers

The Book Depository collects the details provided by you on registration together with information we learn about you from your use of our service and your visits to our web site and other sites accessible from them. We also collect information about the transactions you undertake including details of payment cards used.

We may collect additional information in connection with your participation in any promotions or competitions offered by us and information you provide when giving us feedback or completing profile forms. We also monitor customer traffic patterns and site use which enables us to improve the service we provide. 

**What we do with the information we gather**  
We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons: 

  * Internal record keeping.
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We may periodically send promotional email about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
  * From time to time, and if you've opted-in, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or post.
  * We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.
  * We will use sales data to populate our 'live sales' map. This is completely anonymous and is only ever displayed at a country level. No correlation could be made between a specific customer's purchase and the book displayed on screen and is not dissimilar to other 'recently sold' displays on many websites.

**Use of your information and your preferences**  
We will use your information to provide and personalise our service. We will also use your contact details to communicate with you. We may use your information to send you offers and news about products and services. Once you have registered to use The Book Depository Ltd, you will be provided with access to a "My account" page that will allow you to tailor our communications to your preferences.

To change your contact preferences simply click "My Account" at the top of the page and click "My contact preferences". If you do not want to receive commercial marketing communications from us, please select your choices by using the boxes available on that page. Please note you will still receive transactional emails from us.

We like to hear your views to help us improve our service. From time to time, we may contact you by email to ask your opinions. Again, if you do not want to be contacted for this purpose, please make your choice on the "Contact preferences" page.

Please note that there may be instances where it may be necessary for us to communicate with you, in any event, for administrative or operational reasons relating to our service.

For e-mail notifications of out of stock titles we will only use your e-mail address for this purpose and not for additional marketing. 

**Your interactions**  
If you decide to delete your account/leave The Book Depository your personal account details will be deleted. Any reviews you have written will not be deleted but default to 'anonymous'.

**Security**  
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

**How we use cookies**  
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

The Book Depository uses cookies for a number of purposes, for instance to enable us to simplify the logging on process for registered users, to help ensure the security and authenticity of registered users, to provide the mechanisms for online shopping and to enable traffic monitoring.

This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

Non-registered visitors of the site are sent anonymous cookies to keep track of their browsing patterns and build up a demographic profile. In addition, any visitor who has clicked on a The Book Depository advertisement on another site that links to The Book Depository will be sent a semi-persistent (e.g. 30 days lifetime) anonymous cookie that will allow us to analyse advertising effectiveness and manage our relationship with affiliate sites.

While you do not need to allow your browser to accept cookies in order to browse much of our web site or to access many of our services, you must have cookies enabled if you wish to shop online or access any areas reserved for registered users.

You can find out more about the way cookies work on [http://www.cookiecentral.com](http://www.cookiecentral.com/).

**Data transfer**  
Under the Data Protection Act 1998, The Book Depository Ltd is required to tell you if it transfers or intends to transfer information which it holds about you to countries outside the European Economic Area ("EEA").

The Book Depository Ltd is a subsidiary of Amazon.com, Inc. Amazon.com, Inc. and its controlled subsidiaries are participants in the Safe Harbour programme developed by the US Department of Commerce and the European Union. Amazon has certified that they adhere to the Safe Harbour Privacy Principles agreed upon by the US and the EU. For more information about the Safe Harbour and to view the certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbour website. If you would like to learn more about the Safe Harbour programme, please send an e-mail to safeharbor@amazon.com. The Book Depository Ltd shares information only as described below, with its parent company Amazon.com, Inc. and the subsidiaries which Amazon.com, Inc., controls and that are either subject to this Privacy Notice or follow practices at least as protective as those described in this Privacy Policy.

The Book Depository Limited currently transfers such information outside the EEA for secure storage on its servers which are currently located in the United States. Because The Book Depository Ltd servers are located in the United States, the transfer of all of The Book Depository Ltd data (including the personal details contained in your account) outside the EEA is necessary to enable The Book Depository Ltd to operate its website and provide products and information to you.

By accessing and using The Book Depository Ltd website you are deemed to have accepted The Book Depository Ltd Terms and Conditions of Use, and to have consented to the transfer and storage of your personal information and data outside the EEA. If you do not wish any of your personal data or information to be stored or transferred outside the EEA, you may withdraw your consent to such at any time by notifying The Book Depository Ltd Customer Service Manager at the address at the end of this page. However, because The Book Depository Ltd servers are located outside the EEA, if you withdraw your consent, The Book Depository Ltd will no longer be able to provide you access to or use of its website. 

**Links to other websites**  
Our website may contain links to enable you to visit other websites of interest easily. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

**Controlling your personal information**  
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

  * whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
  * if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at via our Contact us page.

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about our group of companies which we think you may find interesting.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to:

Customer Services Manager,  
The Book Depository Limited,  
Goodridge Business Park,  
Gloucester,  
GL2 5EB

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us via the Contact us page as soon as possible, or at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

 _Back to top_
